Adrian Florescu

Bucharest, Bucharest, Romania



florescuadyz@yahoo.com



40729977759



linkedin.com/in/adrianflorescu

Summary

I'm a Front-end Developer living in Bucharest, Romania. Building web apps for more than a decade. Coding HTML, CSS, and JavaScript with all the flavors like React, Sass, Typescript, and also fiddling with backend technologies like Node.js or PHP. Design-driven, where every detail counts and user experience is always first.

Tech stack:

CODING

React with Typescript, SASS, and HTML

BUILD / DevOps

Webpack, NPM, Travis, Git, Docker

SERVER SIDE

Node.js usually with Express.js

DESIGN

Familiar with Photoshop, Sketch, Figma, etc and I also like to design web apps or features in existing apps that I work on from time to time

USED IN THE PAST

Backbone.js, Angular.js, Vue.js, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, Grunt, Gulp, Cordova

Website: https://www.adrianf.com

Experience



Senior Frontend Developer

IBM

Jan 2018 - Apr 2020 (2 years 4 months)

Worked on a financial planning application. This app has a custom framework that enabled the concept of "micro frontends" where each team can develop its own stuff in isolation from other teams.

- Implemented the designs and features into the app
- Developed a library where each team can publish their own react components and use across the organization
- Won an innovation award for building a grid-like component that needed to handle around 30-40 thousand nodes all on a single render
- Participated in an IBM program called "Everyday Leadership" that helped me develop my soft skills like speaking in public, communicating with colleagues, and many more

Technologies used: React, Redux, Typescript, Unit Tests (Jest and react-testing-library), Docker, Travis CI, NPM, Semantic-Release

vivre Front-end Developer

Vivre Deco

Feb 2015 - Dec 2017 (2 years 11 months)

Goals:

Make online shopping experience a breeze on our apps.

I work on multiple platforms/disciplines. Not only design and front-end but also into the native capabilities of your mobile phone with Cordova.

Important milestones timeline:

2017

- Moved all front-end to Node/JavaScript and released a fully responsive layout
- Designed and implemented the client-side functionality for the new return form where users can quickly return products bought on our website

2016

- Migrated the front-end to NODE.js with server-side rendering and client-side hydration (Backbone and Handlebars)
- Migrated (for some pages) the view engine from Handlebars to Vue.js
- Better development flows with NPM and Webpack (Hot Reload for Vue pages, CSS injection)
- I started implementing a new responsive design project with the technologies above

2015

- Built and launched the Vivre hybrid Mobile App that right now you can find on the Google Play Store or
- Designed and implemented features and sections of the website/app
- Implemented build tools for minification and SASS pre-processing, or email generators (Webpack, Gulp, NPM)



Front-end Engineer

Adrian Florescu

Apr 2013 - Jan 2015 (1 year 10 months)

Working from home is an exhausting thing, but an interesting experience.

All this time I've been working with my past employers, LandmarkGroup, Prologue, and Ten.ro on some wonderful projects like www.landmarkshops.com, www.dbi2015romania.com, www.prices.ae, and others.



May 2012 - Apr 2013 (1 year)

Worked on launching the LandmarkShops.com project.

My main role was to convert all the designs into HTML, CSS, and JS but I also designed some of the modules of the website.

It was a challenging experience and I've learned a ton of JS while building the user interactions, shopping basket experience, store locator, wishlist, etc.

Web Designer / Front-end Developer

Prologue Advertising

Dec 2011 - May 2012 (6 months)

Excited to be working on lots of projects, always having something new to do, and being challenged by coworkers.

Designer - I was pushing pixels in Photoshop to create beautiful websites.

Developer - Taking the pixels and converting them into clean & semantic HTML, CSS, and JS/jQuery and for some projects even going a step forward and integrating all this into WordPress.

Web Designer

Adrian Florescu

Jan 2007 - Dec 2011 (5 years)

Working my way through college while designing websites & building them into HTML, CSS & JS.

I also did a lot of print design for banners.

Working for free and learning things online at the beginning made me realize that the web is fun and I wanted to start doing this as something more than just a hobby.

Education



University of Bucharest

Bachelor of Science (BS), Geology and Geophysics 2007 - 2011

Skills

CSS • HTML • JavaScript • HTML5 • TypeScript • React.js • Vue.js